<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Carlos Yanez Santibanez</title>
    <link>https://www.carlosyanez.id.au/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Carlos Yanez Santibanez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 10:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.carlosyanez.id.au/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Data Governance</title>
      <link>https://www.carlosyanez.id.au/2022/05/on-data-governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 10:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.carlosyanez.id.au/2022/05/on-data-governance/</guid>
      <description>Photo by fabio on Unsplash
With the massification of the Internet and the advent of digital technologies, the ability to process large volumes of data has become a key aspect of how organisations (private and government) conduct their businesses. By becoming data-driven, private companies, government and not-for-profit institutions aim to gain insight and create value for their stakeholders. However, this task is not always easy: according to Accenture, many organisations find it difficult to derive value from data, which can be expressed as a gap between the actual and potential value of their data assets (Accenture 2019).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data Analytics and Personal Data</title>
      <link>https://www.carlosyanez.id.au/2022/05/data-analysis/big-data-analytics-and-personal-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.carlosyanez.id.au/2022/05/data-analysis/big-data-analytics-and-personal-data/</guid>
      <description>As part of my uni studies, I had to prepare a presentation on how big data analytics has to consider existing data privacy regulations. This work was done based on the UK&amp;rsquo;s Data Protection Act 1998, but these principles also exist in the current UK GDPR and other frameworks like (EU) GDPR or the Australian Privacy Principles.
The direct link to the presentation is here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to watch on Netflix ?</title>
      <link>https://www.carlosyanez.id.au/2021/04/data-analysis/what-to-watch-on-netflix/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 09:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.carlosyanez.id.au/2021/04/data-analysis/what-to-watch-on-netflix/</guid>
      <description>View full screen here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycle Spaces in Melbourne</title>
      <link>https://www.carlosyanez.id.au/2020/11/data-analysis/bicycle-spaces-in-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.carlosyanez.id.au/2020/11/data-analysis/bicycle-spaces-in-melbourne/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messi</title>
      <link>https://www.carlosyanez.id.au/posts/2020/11/data-analysis/messi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 21:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.carlosyanez.id.au/posts/2020/11/data-analysis/messi/</guid>
      <description>Back in August, the press informed that Lionel Messi wanted to leave FC Barcelona, the only team in his professional career. Barcelona was not ready to let him go without a fight, and eventually he was convinced (or his lawyers were convinced) he should stay for a least another season.
Being one of the most relevant football player of his generation, he attracts a lot of business opportunities for Barcelona - so the financial reasons for trying him to stay are obvious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locked down areas in Melbourne</title>
      <link>https://www.carlosyanez.id.au/posts/2020/06/locked-down-areas-in-melbourne/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 09:22:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.carlosyanez.id.au/posts/2020/06/locked-down-areas-in-melbourne/</guid>
      <description>Updated on 4 July 2020: added postcodes 3031 and 3051.
From midnight Wednesday, 10 Melbourne postcode areas will enter lockdown, to contain the spread of covid-19. As per the news report, the areas are 3012, 3021, 3032, 3038, 3042, 3046, 3047, 3055, 3060, 3064.
Although my postcode is not listed, it is in one of previously mentioned hot spot LGAs. So, to better understand which are exactly the places in lock down, I put them in the above map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desigualdad en Chile</title>
      <link>https://www.carlosyanez.id.au/posts/2019/12/desigualdad-en-chile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 11:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.carlosyanez.id.au/posts/2019/12/desigualdad-en-chile/</guid>
      <description>_ English version here._
tldr: Sí, los ingresos se distribuyen de manera desigual en Chile. Esto es especialmente cierto en comparación con naciones desarrolladas, pero no es extraordinario en el contexto latinoamericano. Observado por decil de ingresos, existe una brecha aguda entre los grupos más pobres y más ricos. Sin embargo, debemos reconocer que tanto la desigualdad como el ingreso han mejorado en los últimos 25 años en todos los grupos de la sociedad: Chile es una historia de éxito.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inequality in Chile</title>
      <link>https://www.carlosyanez.id.au/posts/2019/12/inequality-in-chile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 14:25:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.carlosyanez.id.au/posts/2019/12/inequality-in-chile/</guid>
      <description>Leer en español aquí.
**tldr: **Yes, income is distributed unequally in Chile. This is especially true when compared with developed nations but it is not unique - countries in Latin America have the same issue. Observed by income deciles, there is an acute gap between the poorest and wealthiest groups. However, we need to acknowledge that both inequality and income for all groups have only become better in the last 25 years - Chile is a success story.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
